KARIM NAGUIB

Permanent Address 3244 Anderson Crescent Mississauga, ON, CA, L5N 2Y5 Contact Information
naguib.karim@gmail.com
Cell: +1 416 557-1622

PROFILE

Karim has 3 years' experience in project management, database development, software development and testing. Karim portrays eagerness to learn, stays proactive and demonstrates an optimistic attitude towards all assignments. Karim is regularly commended on his professionalism and work ethos, presentation skills, ability to integrate smoothly with a new team, and bring positive energy.

A graduate of the University of Waterloo, with a degree in Management Engineering, Karim is well versed with supply chain network design, optimization, software delivery and management of information systems.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Applied Science, *Honours Management Engineering*, Co-operative Program, University of Waterloo, Waterloo, ON, Sept. 2010 – June 2015

Graduate from the Institute of Trading and Portfolio Management in 2014, mentored by Anton Kreil

• <u>Concepts Learned:</u> Statistical Distribution of Asset Returns, Implied and OHLC Volatility Assessment across Equities, Currencies, and Commodities; Risk Management, Beta Hedging (Equities), Portfolio Construction

WORK EXPERIENCE

Business Technology Consultant

Deloitte - Toronto - December 2015 - Present

Client - Metrolinx

Position – *Functional Analyst*

Metrolinx, an agency of the Government of Ontario is responsible for all modes of transportation in the Greater Toronto and Hamilton Area. The client selected Deloitte to provide advisory and delivery services for their e-Ticketing & Visual Display management systems.

- Acting as a "Subject Matter Expert" in client meetings to determine the feasibility and design considerations for the third phase of enhancements, to the e-ticketing system rolled out in June 2015
- Documenting requirements gathered and preparing the functional specification document, which will be later shared with the technical architect
- Conducted multiple presentations with the client illustrating proposed business processes through the use of flow charts and designing mock-ups for proposed UI changes

Client - <u>Janssen: Pharmaceutical Companies of Johnson & Johnson</u>
Position - <u>Testing and Development Operations Lead</u>

The client selected Deloitte to provide advisory and delivery services for their Patient Support program through a Salesforce.com implementation.

- Managed version control, branching strategy and continuous integration. Technologies used include: Bitbucket, SourceTree, Jenkins and Git
- Initiated the automated regression testing project. Technologies used include: Java, Selenium, Cucumber, and Apache Maven
- Played a vital role in release management activities. Automated a number of tasks by leveraging Apache
 Ant; resulting in much smoother error free deployments
- Responsible for SIT throughout project sprints and seeing user stories through to UAT

• Acted as a developer when needed; developed a number of Visualforce pages (HTML and CSS based) with their respective Apex Controllers (Java)

eFX Quantitative Analyst (Intern)

Scotiabank Global Banking and Markets - Toronto - Sept 2014 - December 2014

- Collaborated in designing and developing an algorithm called the "Interpreted Market Price"; Algorithm
 analyzes the behavior of prices aggregated from liquidity providers then determines the "true" market price,
 which the trading algorithms use when deciding which LP to hedge with
- Implementation of the "Interpreted Market Price" algorithm increased the trade desk's average daily P&L by \$1100 due to the reduction of rejections when hedging
- Developed a multi-threaded Java SWING application which monitors the trade desk's Algo trading engines;
 - o Allows the team to monitor and ensure algorithms are trading within the specified risk parameters
- Developed a multi-threaded WPF application that plots prices aggregated from Liquidity Providers real-time;
 - o Allows the traders to monitor spreads throughout the trading day in a simple visual format
- Developed a WPF C# application which analyzes trade execution, and spread quality. Data was presented visually;
 - Used to determine which liquidity providers are rejecting/showing unfavorable prices etc.

eFX Quantitative Analyst (Intern)

Scotiabank Global Banking and Markets, Toronto, Jan 2014 - April 2014

- Developed a multi-threaded trade analysis application used to analyze client deals; (WPF C# application)
 - o Tool allowed traders to better assess the risk of market movement from particular client trades
- Gained an excellent understanding of the sell side FX business, through daily interaction with sales and trading

FX Analyst

Sterling Investments Group LP, Mississauga, August 2013 – December 2014

- Regularly compiled and analyzed daily news events and industry trends from sources such as Bloomberg etc.
- Quarterly presentations were conducted presenting macroeconomic news updates, as well as forecasts for currency movements in the upcoming quarter

Quality Assurance Analyst (Intern)

Bank of America Merrill Lynch, Toronto, May 2013 – August 2013

Designed and developed test scripts using the Selenium and TestNG framework (Java Development)

SYSTEM EXPERIENCE

Software/products:

Visual Studio, Eclipse, Android Studio, Bitbucket, Jenkins, SourceTree, Salesforce.com, Bloomberg Terminal

Development tools/languages:

C#, Java, VBA, SQL, XAML, XML, WPF, Java SWING, Android, Salesforce Apex, Salesforce Visualforce, HTML, CSS, JSON, JavaScript, JQuery, Selenium, Cucumber, Git, Apache Maven, Apache Ant

OS/Middleware/databases:

Windows, MS SQL Server

LANGUAGE SKILLS

English - *Native* **Arabic** - *Native*

French - Basic Conversation